Hi everybody I'm John Graden from the Martial Arts Teacher's Association.
Today I want to talk to you for just a few moments about rhythm in fighting.
As you become, as you gain more experience as a coach and as a fighter you start to sense various rhythms with fighters.
Some rhythms are very complimentary and some are the exact opposite.
For instance some fighters have what I call a spastic rhythm about them.
They're just kind of, they're all over the place.
You know if you were trying to shoot them it is kind of hard to get them.
Often they are out of position though.
A lot of guys that are real spastic are rarely in good position to be able to fire.
Other guys and I think I'm included in this have a much more flowing kind of rhythm.
The danger with a flowing kind of rhythm is that it can become kind of predictable.
So if you are like me and you are kind of a flowing rhythmic fighter you are going to make sure that you are always sticking in little fakes, little feints to throw your opponent's aim off, throw their set point off.
So here's an example of where you can use rhythm to your advantage.
Watch this.
Joining me from Pro Star Mixed Martial Arts is Mr. Joe Brignoli.
This is a sneaky trick.
This is a rhythm drill.
Let's say that as we are moving around I sucker him into a false rhythm, just kind of hold your ground.
So we are moving and I'm going to go in and out, one, and I'm going to go in and out two, and I'm going to go in, bang, fake out and step in.
So I have used a broken rhythm.
This was first developed by Bruce Lee, taught to Joe Louis, who taught it to me and I'm teaching it to you so you have got a good family tree.
Watch this again.
This is a broken rhythm attack, in and out, in and out, in, fake out pow, fire, right and left, right and left, fake right, go left so learn your rhythm, learn to ascertain the rhythm of your opponent and then get sneaky with it.
That is called a broken rhythm attack.
I'm John Graden.
For information contact me at johngraden.com.
Thanks.